<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0.29" dur="3.08">The more frugal travelers among us might be
pleased to know that there are pockets of</text><text start="3.37" dur="3.65">the world where a few weeks of luxury can
come at a fairly moderate price.</text><text start="7.02" dur="4.039">According to a 2017 cost of living survey
if you want to live large and spend very little</text><text start="11.059" dur="1.2">you might head over to India.</text><text start="12.259" dur="3.361">On the other hand, the budget-minded traveler
should probably give Switzerland or Norway</text><text start="15.62" dur="1">a wide berth.</text><text start="16.62" dur="3.46">Fast food lovers might also check out the
Big Mac Index, an informal way to compare</text><text start="20.08" dur="2.06">the Purchasing-Power Parity of a country.</text><text start="22.14" dur="4.78">Switzerland has the most expensive Big Mac
in the world at $6.59, while Ukrainians can</text><text start="26.92" dur="2.11">enjoy the cheapest at $1.57.</text><text start="29.03" dur="3.409">Today we’ll be looking at the cost of things,
in this episode of the Infographics Show:</text><text start="32.439" dur="1.541">What a Dollar Gets You Around the World.</text><text start="33.98" dur="2.5">Don’t forget to subscribe and click the
bell button so that you can be part of our</text><text start="36.48" dur="1.18">Notification Squad.</text><text start="37.66" dur="3.5">While McDonald&amp;#39;s fans might be disappointed
that nowhere on Earth sells a Big Mac for</text><text start="41.16" dur="4.53">a buck, aficionados of ice cream are in for
a treat if they visit Croatia.</text><text start="45.69" dur="3.54">In 2016, the country’s Ledo Hešteg ice
cream won the gold medal at the International</text><text start="49.23" dur="1.99">Ice Cream Consortium held in Barcelona.</text><text start="51.22" dur="3.87">One large scoop of this champion bonne bouche
will set you back exactly one dollar.</text><text start="55.09" dur="4.28">Croatians earn on average just over 800 dollars
a month, which is very low for a developed</text><text start="59.37" dur="1">nation.</text><text start="60.37" dur="2.8">According to the United Nations Economic Commission
for Europe, the Swiss are the highest earners</text><text start="63.17" dur="4.76">in the world with an average monthly full-time
gross salary of $7,396.</text><text start="67.93" dur="3.54">We know eating at McDonalds in this country
is relatively expensive, but what can a Swiss</text><text start="71.47" dur="1.38">resident get for a dollar?</text><text start="72.85" dur="2.46">Not much, according to Swiss online grocery
stores.</text><text start="75.31" dur="4.37">After searching high and low we found that
Swiss dogs can eat well for buck, with a small</text><text start="79.68" dur="4.92">can of Beef &amp;amp; Lamb Flavored Terrine adult
canine cuisine costing a fraction under one</text><text start="84.6" dur="1.33">U.S. dollar.</text><text start="85.93" dur="3.09">In 2016, Australia was ranked as the most
expensive place to live in the world if you</text><text start="89.02" dur="2.849">want to have what was called “low-level
mid-week fun”.</text><text start="91.869" dur="1.911">Well, at least wine is cheap over there.</text><text start="93.78" dur="4.71">The BBC once reported that wine was cheaper
than water in Australia, while in 2017 Cheapa</text><text start="98.49" dur="3.96">Wines at Melbourne’s Preston Market was
reported to be selling a bottle of white wine</text><text start="102.45" dur="1.87">for under one U.S. dollar.</text><text start="104.32" dur="3.53">Australia is also the land of cheap sausage
rolls, where an Ozzie can enjoy a Woolworth’s</text><text start="107.85" dur="2.05">Snowy River Sausage Roll for just a buck.</text><text start="109.9" dur="3.44">The average monthly wage in Australia is one
of the highest in the world at around 5,000</text><text start="113.34" dur="1.69">U.S. dollars per month.</text><text start="115.03" dur="2.15">Australians earn on average a little more
than Americans.</text><text start="117.18" dur="4.31">The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics reported
in 2016 the average wage for an American worker</text><text start="121.49" dur="4.11">was $3,679 per month for a 40-hour work week.</text><text start="125.6" dur="2.32">What can Americans get for one of their own
dollars?</text><text start="127.92" dur="3.48">According to one website, U.S. bargain-hunting
citizens can buy plenty of nice things for</text><text start="131.4" dur="1">a dollar.</text><text start="132.4" dur="3.89">In 2017, if Americans look hard enough, for
a buck they can buy a pair of earrings, a</text><text start="136.29" dur="4.279">city-to-city trip with Megabus, perfumes on
Ebay and a pregnancy test kit, among many</text><text start="140.569" dur="1.361">more items that were listed.</text><text start="141.93" dur="3.77">Heading over to the Far East in Hong Kong,
one slice of plastic-wrapped crustless bread</text><text start="145.7" dur="1">costs a dollar.</text><text start="146.7" dur="5.149">Hong Kong is notoriously expensive, and its
average salary of around $3,500 a month isn’t</text><text start="151.849" dur="1">spectacular.</text><text start="152.849" dur="2.78">A lack of space is one reason for the high
cost of living in Hong Kong.</text><text start="155.629" dur="5.5">In June of this year, a car parking spot was
sold for a staggering $664,000.</text><text start="161.129" dur="3.62">The good news is you can take the trip across
and back from the main island and see that</text><text start="164.749" dur="1.83">famous view of the city’s skyscraper.</text><text start="166.579" dur="3.751">A return journey with Star Ferry will cost
you a little less than one U.S. dollar.</text><text start="170.33" dur="3.449">Sticking to the magical East, let’s have
a look at Thailand, a country renowned for</text><text start="173.779" dur="2.911">beautiful beaches suited to budgeting backpackers.</text><text start="176.69" dur="4.869">According to a poll, the average salary in
Thailand is around $1,205 US dollars per month,</text><text start="181.559" dur="3.4">and while wages can be high in the capital
of Bangkok, the cost of living in Thailand</text><text start="184.959" dur="3.78">for the most part is low because much of the
population earns a meager income.</text><text start="188.739" dur="4.03">For this reason, Thailand’s famed cuisine
can come at little cost, with a bowl of noodles</text><text start="192.769" dur="3.12">or a rice dish available from a street stall
at around one dollar.</text><text start="195.889" dur="1.52">Drinking water is usually free.</text><text start="197.409" dur="3.73">This is vital as low wage earners such as
construction workers from neighboring Burma</text><text start="201.139" dur="4.33">are often paid less than 10 U.S. dollars for
an entire day’s work in the hot sun.</text><text start="205.469" dur="2.291">Cheap staples are a necessity in many developing
nations.</text><text start="207.76" dur="3.5">If you want a loaf of bread for one dollar,
head to Iraq, Yemen and Zimbabwe.</text><text start="211.26" dur="3.28">Gambia has the cheapest bread at just 17 cents
a loaf on average.</text><text start="214.54" dur="3.5">You can also buy a little over 2 lbs (1 kilo)
of potatoes in Gambia for just under one dollar.</text><text start="218.04" dur="1">It’s a cheap country, and needs to be when
the average wage is only about $768 a month...that’s</text><text start="219.04" dur="1">$.60 an hour!</text><text start="220.04" dur="1">Eggs are also something in the diet of most
global citizens.</text><text start="221.04" dur="4.279">According to the US Bureau of Labor Statistics
one dozen eggs in 2016 were sold at a global</text><text start="225.319" dur="1.681">average of $1.46.</text><text start="227" dur="2.859">If you want a dozen eggs for a dollar head
to Pakistan.</text><text start="229.859" dur="4.44">Pakistanis earn a little above $125 a month
on average, so things need to be cheap.</text><text start="234.299" dur="4.071">In Pakistan you can also buy 2.2 lbs of rice
for just over a buck, or for the same amount</text><text start="238.37" dur="1.849">take 5 trips on local buses.</text><text start="240.219" dur="3.83">As for beer to go with your eggs and bread,
according to a database of World Beer Prices,</text><text start="244.049" dur="3.321">there are many countries where the amber nectar
is less than one dollar per bottle.</text><text start="247.37" dur="2.769">But a lot depends on where you buy it, i.e.
bar or store.</text><text start="250.139" dur="3.91">In terms of the overall price of beer, the
cheapest place is the capital city of Slovakia,</text><text start="254.049" dur="2.09">Bratislava, at just over one dollar.</text><text start="256.139" dur="3.152">The average wage in Slovakia is around 1,000
American dollars a month.</text><text start="259.291" dur="4.269">For just under a buck you can also buy a 2.2
lbs of potatoes or a liter of milk.</text><text start="263.56" dur="3.071">Keeping with the theme of bad habits, the
cheapest place in the world to buy a pack</text><text start="266.631" dur="4.709">of Marlboro Red cigarettes in 2016 was Nigeria
at around 76 cents.</text><text start="271.34" dur="3.7">Nigerians can also enjoy three cans of coke
for just over a dollar, a loaf of bread, and</text><text start="275.04" dur="3.84">provided they live 1 km from the shop, they
can get a taxi for just one dollar.</text><text start="278.88" dur="3.77">The average wage in Nigeria is around $300
per month, with its minimum wage being one</text><text start="282.65" dur="2.52">of the lowest in the world at $.36 an hour.</text><text start="285.17" dur="3.62">Compare that to the modern Scandinavian nation
of Finland, where for one dollar you can make</text><text start="288.79" dur="2.75">use of a pristine porcelain bowl in a public
bathroom.</text><text start="291.54" dur="4">The same amount of money in this country,
that has an average monthly wage of around</text><text start="295.54" dur="2.9">3,700 U.S. dollars, will buy you 2.2 lbs of
potatoes.</text><text start="298.44" dur="3.52">Over the border in notoriously expensive Norway,
a dollar won’t get you very far.</text><text start="301.96" dur="3.86">As we did with Switzerland, we had to dig
deep to find one dollar deals in Norway, but</text><text start="305.82" dur="3.01">found that you can buy a packet of Ramen noodles
for that amount.</text><text start="308.83" dur="4.05">Norwegians are high earners in terms of the
global average, bringing in around $4,166</text><text start="312.88" dur="1.6">U.S. dollars a month.</text><text start="314.48" dur="3.93">We found in Japan, a country certainly not
synonymous with the word cheap, at the Japanese</text><text start="318.41" dur="4.09">version of the dollar store you can pick up
a pair of fetching slippers, a pair of swimming</text><text start="322.5" dur="2.32">goggles, as well as an array of Hello Kitty
merchandise.</text><text start="324.82" dur="2.99">Japan’s average wage is around 3,000 dollars
per month.</text><text start="327.81" dur="3.5">Once you are fed, clothed, and ready for some
rest, why not go watch a movie?</text><text start="331.31" dur="3.54">According to a survey, residents of Turkmenistan
could have watched the highest grossing movie</text><text start="334.85" dur="2.93">in 2015, Guardians of the Galaxy, for just
one dollar.</text><text start="337.78" dur="3.65">Bear in mind though, the average monthly salary
for a Turkman when that movie came out was</text><text start="341.43" dur="2.25">around 200 U.S. dollars a month.</text><text start="343.68" dur="3.47">And so, we come to the end of the show, knowing
that in some countries a fistful of American</text><text start="347.15" dur="3.82">dollars is enough to have a grand old time,
and in other places, a buck alone is a paltry</text><text start="350.97" dur="1">thing.</text><text start="351.97" dur="2.28">We hope you’ve had fun, and please let us
know in the comments what you can buy for</text><text start="354.25" dur="1.45">one dollar in your own country.</text><text start="355.7" dur="3.71">And if you liked this video, be sure to check
out our other video called Americans vs Europeans!</text><text start="359.41" dur="3.15">Thanks for watching, and, as always, don’t
forget to like, share, and subscribe.</text><text start="362.56" dur="0.58">See you next time!</text></transcript>