<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="1.09" dur="5.41">The Washington State Recycling Association
claims that in 2011 the United States threw</text><text start="6.5" dur="4.43">more than 36 million tons of food waste into
landfills.</text><text start="10.93" dur="5.18">When these food remains break down, they contribute
significantly to the production of methane,</text><text start="16.11" dur="5.3">which is a powerful greenhouse gas that is
known to be one of the causes of climate change.</text><text start="21.41" dur="4.379">Using food scraps previously destined for
the trash helps you reduce that waste and</text><text start="25.789" dur="5.141">saves you money in the long run, leading to
a happy planet and a fuller bank account.</text><text start="30.93" dur="1.929">What kind of food scraps?</text><text start="32.859" dur="5.211">Think of things like citrus rinds, sourdough
starter, and of course, eggshells.</text><text start="38.07" dur="4.37">When looking for ways to cut down on kitchen
waste, there are likely many solutions that</text><text start="42.44" dur="2.31">come to mind before using eggshells.</text><text start="44.75" dur="5.52">However, eggshells can be incredibly useful
in a number of ways around the home and garden.</text><text start="50.27" dur="4.67">DIY enthusiasts everywhere recommend sprinkling
coarsely ground eggshells in your garden to</text><text start="54.94" dur="3.75">dissuade or eliminate any pests who are eating
the plants.</text><text start="58.69" dur="2.73">An all-natural, eco-friendly pest repellent?</text><text start="61.42" dur="1.069">Score!</text><text start="62.489" dur="4.321">Deer are incredibly sensitive to the scent
of eggs, and if you&amp;#39;re having a problem with</text><text start="66.81" dur="5.11">neighborhood cats using your garden as a litter
box, eggshells will discourage them as well,</text><text start="71.92" dur="3.729">since they find the broken shells uncomfortable
to step on.</text><text start="75.649" dur="4.771">Ground eggshells also work in a way similar
to diatomaceous earth for keeping out smaller</text><text start="80.42" dur="5.869">insects that crawl along the ground, essentially
creating your own chemical free insecticide.</text><text start="86.289" dur="4.091">To use eggshells in your garden as a pest
deterrent, simply crush the shells with a</text><text start="90.38" dur="5.18">rolling pin or coarsely grind them in a food
processor and then sprinkle the broken fragments</text><text start="95.56" dur="2.46">anywhere you have been having problems.</text><text start="98.02" dur="3.75">There&amp;#39;s another bonus here, too: eggshells
are good for your soil!</text><text start="101.77" dur="4.459">Adding crushed eggshells to your soil can
boost the calcium content, which is crucial</text><text start="106.229" dur="3.14">to building healthy, strong plant cell walls.</text><text start="109.369" dur="5.62">Just mix ground eggshells into the soil twice
per year, once in the fall and once in the</text><text start="114.989" dur="4.2">spring, as eggshells take a while to break
down and allow the nutrients to be absorbed</text><text start="119.189" dur="1.38">by the plants.</text><text start="120.569" dur="4.631">Tomato plants especially love calcium, so
be sure to use this trick if you are trying</text><text start="125.2" dur="1.04">to grow them.</text><text start="126.24" dur="6.04">Eggshells also are known to lower the pH content
of overly acidic soils, and help aerate the</text><text start="132.28" dur="4.92">ground — and that is very important, as
the soil can become compacted over time, which</text><text start="137.2" dur="3.319">prevents plant roots from getting the oxygen
they need.</text><text start="140.519" dur="5.121">We&amp;#39;re not done with gardening just yet, as
you can use eggshells for a thrifty, environmentally-friendly</text><text start="145.64" dur="2.67">container to grow plants from seed.</text><text start="148.31" dur="1.62">&amp;quot;I beg your garden.&amp;quot;</text><text start="149.93" dur="1">&amp;quot;What?</text><text start="150.93" dur="1.08">Oh my god I can&amp;#39;t believe it!&amp;quot;</text><text start="152.01" dur="5.16">You can start just about any seed in an eggshell,
and using eggshells for seedlings comes with</text><text start="157.17" dur="5.069">the added bonus of being able to plant the
eggshell along with your young plant directly</text><text start="162.239" dur="5.691">in the soil once it has sprouted leaves and
is ready to be outside on its own.</text><text start="167.93" dur="4.58">Eggshells are compostable and made almost
entirely from calcium carbonate, so as they</text><text start="172.51" dur="5.039">break down the shells will supply your new
plants with the calcium and nitrogen essential</text><text start="177.549" dur="1.72">to helping them develop.</text><text start="179.269" dur="4.151">Just make sure to keep at least half of the
eggshell unbroken to provide enough space</text><text start="183.42" dur="1.73">for your seeds to grow.</text><text start="185.15" dur="4.94">According to Taste of Home, eggshells aren&amp;#39;t
only useful in the garden, but are also really</text><text start="190.09" dur="2.39">great at cleaning up in the kitchen and bathroom.</text><text start="192.48" dur="5.569">You can create your own non-toxic, all natural
abrasive cleaner (similar to household cleaning</text><text start="198.049" dur="3.591">product Ajax) with eggshells and baking soda.</text><text start="201.64" dur="4.929">To create this mix, you will need to dry your
shells out in the sun or in a low oven, and</text><text start="206.569" dur="3.081">then grind the dry shells into a fine powder.</text><text start="209.65" dur="4.64">Mix one cup of powdered eggshells — about
a dozen eggs worth — with three cups of</text><text start="214.29" dur="1.13">baking soda.</text><text start="215.42" dur="4.649">When you are ready to clean, simply combine
the powder mix with a little vinegar or water</text><text start="220.069" dur="5.581">to create an abrasive paste that is safe to
use on pots and pans, showers, and toilet</text><text start="225.65" dur="1.179">bowls.</text><text start="226.829" dur="3.481">Eggshells are great at removing coffee stains
from your thermos, as well.</text><text start="230.31" dur="3.98">Just crush some up and fill your thermos about
a third of the way with the shells and hot</text><text start="234.29" dur="1.69">water and shake.</text><text start="235.98" dur="3.69">Within a few minutes, the stains inside should
begin to dissipate.</text><text start="239.67" dur="2.829">Who would have thought eggshells are so useful?</text><text start="242.499" dur="2.121">Check out one of our newest videos right here!</text><text start="244.62" dur="3.94">Plus, even more Mashed videos about your favorite
foods are coming soon.</text><text start="248.56" dur="4.409">Subscribe to our YouTube channel and hit the
bell so you don&amp;#39;t miss a single one.</text></transcript>