<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="1.11" dur="2.83">The Wizarding World can be a complicated place.</text><text start="3.94" dur="4.43">Welcome to WatchMojo UK and today we’ll
be counting down the Top Ten Harry Potter</text><text start="8.37" dur="5.849">Fan Theories.</text><text start="14.219" dur="4.151">For this list we are focussing on the wildest,
most-thought provoking fan theories related</text><text start="18.37" dur="1.49">to the Harry Potter universe.</text><text start="19.86" dur="2.57">So, wands at the ready, this is going to be
interesting.</text><text start="22.43" dur="8.03">Oh yes, and spoiler alert.</text><text start="30.46" dur="6.97">We’ve probably all heard this at some point,
but what if Hogwarts never existed?</text><text start="37.43" dur="3.78">What if it was all in Harry’s head and he
never left the cupboard under the stairs?</text><text start="41.21" dur="4.88">Given, this is a popular, throwaway theory,
but in this case, it totally makes sense.</text><text start="46.09" dur="5.28">A young boy, constantly isolated and mistreated
by his aunt and uncle - why wouldn&amp;#39;t he create</text><text start="51.37" dur="9.03">a fantasy world of friends and adventures
he was never allowed to have.</text><text start="60.4" dur="1.53">The weird thing is, even J.K.</text><text start="61.93" dur="6.65">Rowling has come out and admitted that this
isn&amp;#39;t the most ridiculous theory.</text><text start="68.58" dur="9.54">Wow, that’s depressing.</text><text start="78.12" dur="3.961">Although there’s no evidence of George hiding
golden tickets in chocolate bars, this is</text><text start="82.081" dur="5.119">still an intriguing theory - and it’s primarily
fuelled by the fact that George uses a Time-Turner</text><text start="87.2" dur="10.959">to travel to a different era and create a
new life for himself.</text><text start="98.159" dur="4.541">Combine that with his pioneering talent for
wacky sweets and the fact that he loses an</text><text start="102.7" dur="9.33">ear - remember, Wonka struggles to hear out
of one ear.</text><text start="112.03" dur="10.82">There’s also an unknown wizardry as to how
some of Wonka’s inventions work.</text><text start="122.85" dur="5.159">I wonder if everything in Wonka’s office
is split in two in homage to George’s brother</text><text start="128.009" dur="1.81">Fred?</text><text start="129.819" dur="7.371">It’s no secret that many Potter fans were
unhappy with the Harry and Ginny love story,</text><text start="137.19" dur="8.409">with many feeling it came out of nowhere.</text><text start="145.599" dur="1.341">Well what if it did?</text><text start="146.94" dur="3.58">Maybe Ginny slipped Harry a love potion to
win his affection.</text><text start="150.52" dur="3.59">Love potions are mentioned throughout Harry
potter, but particularly around the time of</text><text start="154.11" dur="3.88">“The Half Blood Prince”, where Harry and
Ginny’s romance blossoms.</text><text start="157.99" dur="3.94">Even Molly Weasley, Ginny’s mum, admits
to using one in the past.</text><text start="161.93" dur="3.72">Could this be why Harry suddenly feels jealous
of Ginny kissing Dean?</text><text start="165.65" dur="6.919">Or why he feels the need to promptly pursue
her?</text><text start="172.569" dur="8.192">It’s commonly thought throughout both the
books and films that only Harry or Voldemort</text><text start="180.761" dur="4.469">can live, with Sybil Trelawney’s prophecy
stating “either must die at the hand of</text><text start="185.23" dur="3.53">the other for neither can live while the other
survives”.</text><text start="188.76" dur="4.759">But surely this means that if Voldemort is
dead and Harry is alive, there isn’t anyone</text><text start="193.519" dur="8.86">who can actually kill Harry - therefore Harry
is effectively immortal?</text><text start="202.379" dur="4.461">One might think, wow, the legendary wizard
will live forever and have many other wild</text><text start="206.84" dur="1">adventures.</text><text start="207.84" dur="6.2">Sadly, if this is the case, he’d never get
to be reunited with his mum and dad in the</text><text start="214.04" dur="1.52">afterlife.</text><text start="215.56" dur="7.01">Now that might sound like some kind of badass
tattoo, but it stems from “The Tale of the</text><text start="222.57" dur="3.01">Three Brothers” as told in “The Deathly
Hallows”.</text><text start="225.58" dur="4.299">And although the tale is known to parallel
the stories of Voldemort, Snape and Harry,</text><text start="229.879" dur="3.911">it is Death’s involvement that is particularly
interesting.</text><text start="233.79" dur="4.131">Believed to be representative of Dumbledore,
Death is instrumental in the demise of two</text><text start="237.921" dur="2.928">of the brother’s aka Voldemort and Snape.</text><text start="240.849" dur="5.961">Death also gives the third brother, aka Harry,
the invisibility cloak.</text><text start="246.81" dur="1.12">Not convinced?</text><text start="247.93" dur="1">Well J.K.</text><text start="248.93" dur="4.85">Rowling has actually said that this theory
is one of her favourites.</text><text start="253.78" dur="9.94">Rowling never tells us exactly how Voldemort
splits his soul into seven pieces, but the</text><text start="263.72" dur="5.149">process of creating a horcrux is described
as one of the darkest acts imaginable, and</text><text start="268.869" dur="4.38">involves murder, an insidious spell and another
unknown ingredient.</text><text start="273.249" dur="3.521">This theory hypothesizes that that may be
cannibalism.</text><text start="276.77" dur="4.049">Think about it - cannibalism is frequently
referred to as one of the darkest acts of</text><text start="280.819" dur="4.34">man, and is synonymous with gaining strength
from a dead subject.</text><text start="285.159" dur="7.91">And I’m sure we can agree, something like
that is hardly uncharacteristic of The Dark</text><text start="293.069" dur="4.25">lord.</text><text start="297.319" dur="3.681">So we can all agree that Harry’s surrogate
family, The Dursley’s, are pretty much the</text><text start="301" dur="3.869">worst, constantly treating him as an unwanted
outsider.</text><text start="304.869" dur="3.67">Throughout the saga we are lead to believe
this is mainly due to their detestation for</text><text start="308.539" dur="2.31">witches and wizards in the family.</text><text start="310.849" dur="4.38">One theory however, suggests that Harry is
actually the author of his own pain as him</text><text start="315.229" dur="4.041">being a horcrux is the thing that actually
makes The Dursley’s so mean.</text><text start="319.27" dur="3.75">And to be fair, being in the same surroundings
of a piece of Voldemort&amp;#39;s soul is enough to</text><text start="323.02" dur="2.229">make anyone a little unpleasant.</text><text start="325.249" dur="12.67">Just ask Ron.</text><text start="337.919" dur="4.15">With heroes and villains rallying together
towards the end of the series, everyone seems</text><text start="342.069" dur="2.52">to have their place, be it for good or evil.</text><text start="344.589" dur="5.091">Young, socially-conscious Draco on the other
hand, struggles to fit in and seems to spiral</text><text start="349.68" dur="1.989">further into uncertainty.</text><text start="351.669" dur="3.72">And a theory for this behaviour is because
he is a werewolf.</text><text start="355.389" dur="4.441">With his father Lucius being in Voldemort&amp;#39;s
pocket, the theory goes that Voldemort got</text><text start="359.83" dur="4.929">a little peeved off at Lucius and decided
to punish him by sending his droog Fenrir</text><text start="364.759" dur="2.62">Grayback to turn Draco into a werewolf.</text><text start="367.379" dur="10.551">That still doesn&amp;#39;t excuse your early years
Draco.</text><text start="377.93" dur="4.129">The foundations of this theory lie in the
series’ first entry, “The Philosopher&amp;#39;s</text><text start="382.059" dur="11.04">Stone”, and the similarities between Ron
and Hogwarts’ famous headteacher.</text><text start="393.099" dur="3.701">You see Ron’s bravery in the famed chess
game where he plays both a knight and king</text><text start="396.8" dur="5.349">when protecting Harry are reminiscent of Dumbledore’s
role in the war against dark magic.</text><text start="402.149" dur="1.3">But there’s more.</text><text start="403.449" dur="4.491">Both of them are described as looking similar,
with similar hands, nose and physique - plus</text><text start="407.94" dur="9.52">they both share a love for sweets, particularly
Bertie Bott’s Every Flavour Beans.</text><text start="417.46" dur="1">Not convinced?</text><text start="418.46" dur="1.94">Dumbledore used to have red hair.</text><text start="420.4" dur="1.469">Spooky, right?</text><text start="421.869" dur="27.69">Before we unveil our top pick, here are a
few honorable mentions.</text><text start="449.559" dur="3.86">One of the biggest questions in the Harry
Potter series is why do wizards feel the need</text><text start="453.419" dur="4">to hide from non-magic muggles?</text><text start="457.419" dur="3.191">Surely with powerful magic comes the freedom
to do whatever you want.</text><text start="460.61" dur="4.869">Well, one theory suggests that muggles defeated
wizards in a war many years earlier, forcing</text><text start="465.479" dur="5.231">witches and wizards to hide away and ultimately
play by their rules.</text><text start="470.71" dur="5.289">A big determiner for this theory comes at
the end of “the Goblet of Fire”, where</text><text start="475.999" dur="4.361">the Ministry of Magic declares to the British
Prime Minister that they are bringing a dragon</text><text start="480.36" dur="8.17">into the country.</text></transcript>