<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0" dur="6.68">One of the strangest things about relationships is that we&amp;#39;re not free to feel attracted to just anyone.</text><text start="6.68" dur="4.88">We tend to have very strong psychological types that we can&amp;#39;t deviate from.</text><text start="11.56" dur="8.02">All of us carry inside us very specific inner shopping lists, defining what the people we can love need to be like as characters.</text><text start="19.58" dur="3.76">You might think these shopping lists would be focused around lovely requirements.</text><text start="23.34" dur="6.58">Like that our potential lovers would need to be kind, understanding, friendly and from our age and social group.</text><text start="29.92" dur="4.72">But the shopping lists are in fact often a lot weirder and darker.</text><text start="34.64" dur="7.14">We may end up neglecting all sorts of potential candidates, dismissing them as boring or yucky or somehow just wrong</text><text start="41.78" dur="5.82">and heading straight to people whose characteristics are pretty awkward and not conducive to our happiness.</text><text start="47.6" dur="6.02">For example, we may only be able to fall in love with people who are much less clever or responsible than we are.</text><text start="53.66" dur="5.5">Or who are really unreliable, or who are selfish and self-absorbed, or sarcastic and mean.</text><text start="59.16" dur="3.54">It can be very puzzling to those around us and to ourselves.</text><text start="62.7" dur="3.58">Why on earth can&amp;#39;t we settle down with people who are good for us?</text><text start="66.28" dur="5.96">That&amp;#39;s because what we&amp;#39;re looking for in love isn&amp;#39;t necessarily someone who is nice, pure and simple</text><text start="72.24" dur="2.4">but someone who feels familiar.</text><text start="74.64" dur="7.62">And a lot of us learned about love in childhood, at the hands of people who were, in a variety of ways, trouble for us</text><text start="82.26" dur="3.94">and who continue unconsciously to guide our love types.</text><text start="86.2" dur="5.22">Our earliest caregivers give us templates of what it is to love and be loved</text><text start="91.42" dur="3.4">which can cause havoc with our chances of happiness.</text><text start="94.82" dur="4.1">The trickiness in our love types tend to go in one of three ways.</text><text start="98.92" dur="6.42">Let&amp;#39;s imagine dad was cold or violent or abusive, or mom was belittling, unavailable or controlling.</text><text start="105.34" dur="4.04">It was horrible, yet that ends up being what we look for in love.</text><text start="109.38" dur="3.54">Why would we ever repeat something that was deeply uncomfortable?</text><text start="112.92" dur="4.06">Well, because even though it was horrible, it was still a love relationship.</text><text start="116.98" dur="7.36">There was abuse but also, let&amp;#39;s imagine, a degree of familiarity, admiration, attachment and even tenderness.</text><text start="124.34" dur="3.58">They may have been belittling, but it&amp;#39;s what we got used to.</text><text start="127.92" dur="5.98">And now, however illogical it sounds, it doesn&amp;#39;t quite feel right unless it&amp;#39;s kind of awful as well.</text><text start="133.9" dur="5.74">It&amp;#39;s not nice as such, but it feels comfortingly, compellingly familiar.</text><text start="139.64" dur="6.96">Or, imagine the experience firsthand... what it was like to be made to feel terrible, to be humiliated and hurt.</text><text start="146.6" dur="3.46">And then, weirdly, we may end up doing the same thing to someone else.</text><text start="150.06" dur="6.32">Humiliating them in turn, bossing them about, going cold on them just when they&amp;#39;re vulnerable to us.</text><text start="156.38" dur="6.4">It&amp;#39;s as if a primitive part of us thinks that the only way not to be abused is to be the abuser.</text><text start="162.78" dur="7.48">Deep inside the child-like emotional self thinks, the person who did that thing to me was, in a way, the opposite of me,</text><text start="170.26" dur="7.18">and that must be the place of safety, and that&amp;#39;s who I want to be in any relationship.</text><text start="177.44" dur="7.12">When parents cause us trouble, we&amp;#39;re often so keen to get away from it, we develop blocks around all kind of character traits they may have had</text><text start="184.56" dur="4.64">which might actually have been good and actually unrelated to the troublesome traits.</text><text start="189.2" dur="4.22">So, for example, our father might have been belittling but highly intelligent.</text><text start="193.42" dur="4.38">Now, regrettably, anyone intelligent can be seen hugely putting us off.</text><text start="197.8" dur="6.96">Or we always felt our mother was somehow revolted by sexuality, ours especially, but she was really warm and cuddly.</text><text start="204.76" dur="5.14">Now, sadly, anyone who is warm and cuddly is imagined to be punitive around sex</text><text start="209.9" dur="2.78">and hence feels wrong and has to be rejected.</text><text start="212.68" dur="2.82">Our inner love maps are really hard to tease out.</text><text start="215.5" dur="5.18">They certainly don&amp;#39;t spell themselves out, so we have to make efforts to find out what they&amp;#39;re dictating</text><text start="220.68" dur="2.62">so as to free ourselves from their demands.</text><text start="223.3" dur="3.94">The investigation starts, as always, by trying to understand ourselves.</text><text start="227.24" dur="3.56">What did I suffer from at the hands of my early caregivers?</text><text start="230.8" dur="3.72">Am I finding myself drawn to that in adults I fancy?</text><text start="234.52" dur="4.54">Am I causing trouble for people in ways I might have suffered from when I was young?</text><text start="239.06" dur="6.6">Am I putting off certain people because they have traits I associate with people who cause me difficulties as a child?</text><text start="245.66" dur="5.5">Might I in other people find the traits I like without the ones I fear?</text><text start="251.16" dur="5">Emotional health means expanding on the number of people we&amp;#39;re free to fall in love with.</text><text start="256.16" dur="1.98">We learn about love in childhood,</text><text start="258.14" dur="5.7">but we liberate ourselves from the traumas of childhood when we realize we can love in different ways,</text><text start="263.84" dur="5.22">and get used to something that may at first be eerily and challengingly unfamiliar.</text><text start="269.06" dur="5.4">Being happy with someone who is properly and deeply good for us.</text></transcript>