<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0.32" dur="5.68">It&amp;#39;s a playground full of magic kingdoms, 
future worlds and galaxies far, far away.  </text><text start="6" dur="4.56">There is so much to do at Walt Disney World! 
The only question is ... when do you visit?</text><text start="12.16" dur="5.28">2022 is gearing up to be another exciting 
year at the Most Magical Place on Earth!  </text><text start="17.44" dur="3.28">With the opening of Guardians 
of the Galaxy: Cosmic Rewind,  </text><text start="20.72" dur="5.2">the return of the Festival of Fantasy parade 
and Fantasmic!, plus the continuation of the  </text><text start="25.92" dur="5.44">World&amp;#39;s Most Magical Celebration, the 
magic (and fun) is definitely calling!</text><text start="31.36" dur="3.68">If you’re new to the Undercover Tourist channel 
make sure to subscribe and hit  </text><text start="35.04" dur="2.64">the notification icon to see our latest videos.</text><text start="38.96" dur="2.96">So when is the best time to visit Walt Disney World?</text><text start="42.48" dur="5.44">The truth is, there is no one-size-fits-all 
answer to this question. What we can say,  </text><text start="47.92" dur="1.92">and what has always been true, is this:  </text><text start="50.48" dur="4.48">You can have a magical visit to Walt Disney 
World no matter the circumstance or crowd level.</text><text start="56" dur="4.284">In our book, it&amp;#39;s always a good time to visit 
Disney World.</text><text start="60.284" dur="4.231">We&amp;#39;ve visited in every season and have found we can manage crowds just fine</text><text start="64.515" dur="4.032">by following our own tips for skipping the lines at theme parks.</text><text start="69.321" dur="5.084">Visiting when the crowds are low 
(or lower) is still one of the best ways to ensure a great trip.</text><text start="75.134" dur="6.485">But there are other factors, such 
as weather, events, park hours and, of course, your family&amp;#39;s availability, </text><text start="81.619" dur="3.661">that  factor into 
the right time to make your magical trip.</text><text start="85.28" dur="2.64">Keep in mind that Disney is 
still requiring that guests  </text><text start="87.92" dur="3.6">book a separate theme park reservation 
in addition to a theme park ticket.  </text><text start="92.16" dur="4.4">That means it’s a good idea to book your 
theme park tickets as soon as possible,  </text><text start="96.56" dur="4.96">especially if you’ll be visiting during a peak 
period such as spring break, summer or Christmas.  </text><text start="102.32" dur="4.08">Once your theme park tickets are purchased, you 
can make your theme park reservations within  </text><text start="106.4" dur="5.04">the My Disney Experience app. Booking early 
means the best availability for your trip!</text><text start="112.32" dur="2.56">It should come as no surprise that the best time  </text><text start="114.88" dur="4.16">to visit Disney World has historically 
fallen along with school schedules,  </text><text start="119.04" dur="4.08">which is to say, the best time to visit 
is generally when the kids are in school.</text><text start="124.16" dur="5.2">Special events should also be a consideration 
in deciding the best time to visit Disney World.  </text><text start="129.36" dur="5.76">Disney World offers some spectacular events, such 
as the EPCOT International Festival of the Arts.  </text><text start="135.12" dur="3.543">You just might decide you want to plan your 
visit during one or more of them!</text><text start="138.663" dur="6.617">Walt Disney World&amp;#39;s 50th-anniversary celebration is also in 
full swing, and will continue for over a year!</text><text start="148.4" dur="4.56">New rides and attractions can also impact 
crowds. We&amp;#39;ve seen this in recent years with  </text><text start="152.96" dur="5.92">the openings of Avatar: Flight of Passage, Slinky 
Dog Dash and Star Wars: Rise of the Resistance.  </text><text start="159.92" dur="6.48">All of these rides continue to see higher wait 
times and demand. So far, EPCOT is the big-ticket  </text><text start="166.4" dur="6">draw this year, with Guardians of the Galaxy 
— Cosmic Rewind blasting off in summer 2022.</text><text start="177.76" dur="6.08">Here are the best times to Visit Walt Disney World</text><text start="187.68" dur="4.88">Historically, September has been the very 
best month of the year to visit Disney World  </text><text start="192.56" dur="5.12">in terms of crowds because the kids have just 
returned to school. It is still our pick for  </text><text start="197.68" dur="4.48">the best month to visit, but it has become 
a more popular month to visit, most likely  </text><text start="202.16" dur="6">because of Mickey&amp;#39;s Not-So-Scary Halloween Party 
and EPCOT International Food &amp;amp; Wine Festival.  </text><text start="208.16" dur="3.68">Keep in mind that September is also 
the height of Orlando&amp;#39;s rainy season.  </text><text start="212.48" dur="4.48">You should prepare for daily afternoon 
thunderstorms and possibly even more rain.</text><text start="217.84" dur="4.96">Some days in January, and some in 
February, are also great times to visit.  </text><text start="222.8" dur="4.8">The big drawback to visiting at this time 
is historically reduced park hours and often  </text><text start="227.6" dur="4.48">scaled-back entertainment. This is also 
when many rides go through refurbishment.  </text><text start="232.64" dur="4.48">Splash Mountain, Kali River Rapids and 
Disney&amp;#39;s Blizzard Beach have annual  </text><text start="237.12" dur="6.56">Disney World refurbishments around this time — in 
2022, this list also includes Expedition Everest.</text><text start="244.96" dur="5.6">Let&amp;#39;s hop over to the holidays. These are popular 
times for families to make trips to Disney World,  </text><text start="250.56" dur="6.48">and rightly so. The Christmas holiday season 
especially, which runs from mid-November through  </text><text start="257.04" dur="4.8">the first of the new year at Disney World, is 
a wonderful time to visit because the parks are  </text><text start="261.84" dur="5.36">decorated and there are many fun special events. 
Many families love the atmosphere around the  </text><text start="267.2" dur="5.12">holidays, even with the extra crowds. The parks 
are the busiest around the following holidays.</text><text start="273.52" dur="6.08">Well, there you have it — the best times to 
visit Disney World in 2022. Let us know your  </text><text start="279.6" dur="3.454">favorite time of year to visit Disney World 
in the comments below!</text><text start="283.054" dur="0.5">Curious how busy Disney World will be when you plan to visit?</text><text start="284.282" dur="4.341">Check out 
our Crowd Calendar.</text><text start="289.041" dur="5.359">You&amp;#39;ll find more resources to help you plan your Disney World vacation on </text><text start="294.4" dur="5.423">the Undercover Tourist Orlando Planning Guide in the link below.</text><text start="300.613" dur="3.666">Get the exact same tickets for less, no catch, at Undercover Tourist!</text></transcript>