<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="1.44" dur="7.12">At its height, the Roman Empire was home to about 
30% of the world’s population, and in many ways  </text><text start="8.56" dur="5.92">it was the pinnacle of human advancement. Its 
citizens enjoyed the benefits of central heating,  </text><text start="14.48" dur="3.44">concrete, double glazing, 
banking, international trade,  </text><text start="17.92" dur="4.16">and upward social mobility.
Rome became the first city in  </text><text start="22.08" dur="4.16">history with one million inhabitants 
and was a center of technological,  </text><text start="26.24" dur="7.12">legal, and economic progress. An empire impossible 
to topple, stable and rich and powerful.</text><text start="34.24" dur="6.8">Until it wasn’t anymore. First slowly then 
suddenly, the most powerful civilization on earth  </text><text start="41.04" dur="6.48">collapsed. By civilization, we mean a complex 
society where labor is specialized and social  </text><text start="47.52" dur="6.64">classes emerge and which is ruled by institutions. 
Civilisations share a dominant mutual language and  </text><text start="54.16" dur="5.12">culture and domesticate plants and 
animals to feed and sustain large cities,  </text><text start="59.28" dur="2.56">where they often construct impressive monuments.</text><text start="63.12" dur="5.52">Civilization lets us become efficient on large 
scales, collect vast amounts of knowledge,  </text><text start="68.64" dur="6">and put human ingenuity and the natural resources 
of the world to work. Without civilization,  </text><text start="74.64" dur="5.28">most people would never have been born. Which 
makes it a bit concerning that collapse is  </text><text start="79.92" dur="7.28">the rule, not the exception. Virtually all 
civilizations end, on average after 340 years.</text><text start="88.4" dur="5.68">Collapse is rarely nice for individuals. 
Their shared cultural identity is shattered as  </text><text start="94.08" dur="6.4">institutions lose the power to organize people. 
Knowledge is lost, living standards fall, violence  </text><text start="100.48" dur="6">increases and often the population declines. 
The civilization either completely disappears,  </text><text start="106.48" dur="3.36">is absorbed by stronger neighbors 
or something new emerges,  </text><text start="110.4" dur="3.68">sometimes with more primitive 
technology than before.</text><text start="114.08" dur="3.68">If this is how it has been over 
the ages, what about us today?  </text><text start="125.68" dur="4.32">Just as Europeans forgot how to build 
indoor plumbing and make cement,  </text><text start="130" dur="4.8">will we lose our industrial technology, 
and with that our greatest achievements,  </text><text start="134.8" dur="5.68">from one dollar pizza to smartphones or 
laser eye surgery? Will all this go away too?</text><text start="141.52" dur="5.2">Today our cities stretch for thousands of 
square kilometers, we travel the skies,  </text><text start="146.72" dur="6.16">our communication is instant. Industrial 
agriculture with engineered high yield plants,  </text><text start="152.88" dur="6.48">efficient machinery and high potency fertilizer 
feeds billions of people. Modern medicine gives  </text><text start="159.36" dur="5.6">us the longest lifespan we’ve ever had, while 
Industrial technology gives us an unprecedented  </text><text start="164.96" dur="5.2">level of comfort and abundance – even though 
we haven’t yet learned to attain them without  </text><text start="170.16" dur="6.32">destroying our ecosphere. There are arguably 
still different civilizations around today that  </text><text start="176.48" dur="6.48">compete and coexist with each other, but together 
they also form a singular, global civilization.</text><text start="183.76" dur="6.08">But this modern, globalized civilization is even 
more vulnerable in some ways than past empires,  </text><text start="189.84" dur="2.96">because we are much more deeply interconnected.  </text><text start="193.68" dur="5.52">A collapse of the industrialized world literally 
means that the majority of people alive today  </text><text start="199.2" dur="4.96">would perish since without industrial agriculture 
we would no longer be able to feed them.</text><text start="204.96" dur="4.16">And there is an even greater 
risk: What if a collapse were so  </text><text start="209.12" dur="3.68">deeply destructive that we were 
unable to re-industrialize again?  </text><text start="213.44" dur="5.44">What if it ruined our chances of enjoying a 
flourishing future as a multiplanetary species?</text><text start="220.16" dur="4.32">A global civilizational collapse 
could be an existential catastrophe:  </text><text start="224.48" dur="3.52">something that ruins not just the 
lives of everyone alive today,  </text><text start="228" dur="4.64">but all the future generations that could have 
come into being. All the knowledge we might have  </text><text start="232.64" dur="5.6">discovered, the art we might have created, the 
joys we might have experienced, would be lost.</text><text start="239.2" dur="2.08">So, how likely is all of this?</text><text start="242.4" dur="5.28">Let’s start with some good news. While 
civilization collapses have happened regularly,  </text><text start="247.68" dur="5.04">none have ever derailed the course of 
global civilization. Rome collapsed,  </text><text start="252.72" dur="5.6">but the Aksumite Empire or the Teotihuacans 
and of course the Byzantine Empire, carried on.</text><text start="259.28" dur="1.92">What about sudden population crashes?</text><text start="262.24" dur="4.08">So far we have not seen a catastrophe 
that has killed much more than 10% of the  </text><text start="266.32" dur="4.24">global population. No pandemic, 
no natural disaster, no war.  </text><text start="271.2" dur="4.48">The last clear example of a rapid global 
population decrease was the Black Death,  </text><text start="275.68" dur="4.56">a pandemic of the bubonic plague in the fourteenth 
century that spread across the Middle East and  </text><text start="280.24" dur="5.2">Europe and killed a third of all Europeans 
and about 1/10th of the global population.</text><text start="286.24" dur="4">If any event was going to cause the 
collapse of civilization, that should have  </text><text start="290.24" dur="6">been it. But even the Black Death demonstrates 
humanity&amp;#39;s resilience more than its fragility.  </text><text start="297.28" dur="3.6">While the old societies were 
massively disrupted in the short term,  </text><text start="300.88" dur="5.52">the intense loss of human lives and suffering 
did little to negatively impact European economic  </text><text start="306.4" dur="5.84">and technological development in the long run. 
Population size recovered within 2 centuries,  </text><text start="312.24" dur="3.36">and just 2 centuries later, the 
Industrial Revolution began. 
 </text><text start="316.48" dur="6.4">History is full of incredible recoveries from 
horrible tragedies. Take the atomic bombing of  </text><text start="322.88" dur="7.36">Hiroshima during World War 2. 140,000 people were 
killed and 90% of the city was at least partially  </text><text start="330.24" dur="6.8">incinerated or reduced to rubble. But against all 
odds, they made a remarkable recovery! Hiroshima’s  </text><text start="337.04" dur="5.68">population recovered within a decade, and today 
it is a thriving city of 1.2 million people.</text><text start="343.52" dur="4.4">None of this made these horrible events any 
less horrible for those who lived through them.  </text><text start="347.92" dur="4.32">But for us as a species, these 
signs of resilience are good news.</text><text start="353.52" dur="2.88">Why Recovery is Likely Even in the Worst Case</text><text start="357.6" dur="5.84">One thing that’s different from historic collapses 
is that humanity now has unprecedented destructive  </text><text start="363.44" dur="6.08">power: Today’s nuclear arsenals are so powerful 
that an all-out global war could cause a nuclear  </text><text start="369.52" dur="6.24">winter and billions of deaths. Our knowledge 
of our own biology and how to manipulate it  </text><text start="375.76" dur="4.8">is getting so advanced that it is becoming 
possible to engineer viruses as contagious  </text><text start="380.56" dur="5.28">as the coronavirus and as deadly 
as ebola. Increasingly the risk of  </text><text start="385.84" dur="6.56">global pandemics is much higher than in the past.
So we may cause a collapse ourselves and it might  </text><text start="392.4" dur="5.76">be much worse than the things nature has thrown 
at us, so far. But if, say 99% of the population  </text><text start="398.16" dur="5.6">died, would global civilization collapse 
forever? Could we recover from such a tragedy?</text><text start="404.56" dur="5.44">We have some reasons to be optimistic. 
Let’s start with food. There are 1 billion  </text><text start="410" dur="4.96">agricultural workers today so, even if the 
global population fell to just 80 million,  </text><text start="414.96" dur="4.4">it is virtually guaranteed that many 
survivors would know how to produce food.  </text><text start="419.36" dur="4.56">And we don’t need to start at square one because 
we could still use modern high-yield crops.  </text><text start="424.48" dur="6.8">Maize is 10 times bigger than its wild ancestor; 
ancient tomatoes were the size of today’s peas.</text><text start="432.08" dur="3.12">After agriculture, the next step towards recovery  </text><text start="435.2" dur="5.28">would be rebuilding industrial capacity, 
like power grids and automated manufacturing.  </text><text start="441.2" dur="5.52">A huge problem is that our economies of scale make 
it impossible to just pick up where we left off.  </text><text start="447.36" dur="4.4">Many of our high tech industries are 
only functional because of huge demand  </text><text start="451.76" dur="3.84">and intensely interconnected supply 
chains across different continents.  </text><text start="456.48" dur="6">Even if our infrastructure were left unharmed, we 
would make huge steps backwards technologically.</text><text start="462.48" dur="5.6">But then again, we are thinking in larger time 
frames. Industrialization originally happened  </text><text start="468.64" dur="6">12,000 years after the agricultural revolution. So 
if we need to start over after a massive collapse,  </text><text start="474.64" dur="4.64">it shouldn’t be that hard to re-industrialize, 
at least on evolutionary timescales.</text><text start="480.24" dur="4.8">There’s a hitch, though. The Industrial 
Revolution was fuelled, literally, by burning  </text><text start="485.04" dur="6.16">easily-accessible coal and we are still very 
much reliant on it. If we use it all up today,  </text><text start="491.2" dur="3.84">aside from making rapid climate change 
much worse, we could hinder our ability  </text><text start="495.04" dur="5.04">to recover from a huge crisis. So we 
should stop using easy-to-access coal,  </text><text start="500.08" dur="4.4">so it can serve as a civilization 
insurance in case something bad happens.</text><text start="505.52" dur="4.32">Another thing that makes recovery likely is that 
we’d probably have most of the information we  </text><text start="509.84" dur="5.28">need to rebuild civilization. We would certainly 
lose a lot of crucial institutional knowledge,  </text><text start="515.12" dur="4.32">especially on hard drives that nobody could 
read or operate anymore. But a lot of the  </text><text start="519.44" dur="4.8">technological, scientific, and cultural knowledge 
stored in the world&amp;#39;s 2.6 million libraries,  </text><text start="524.24" dur="5.52">would survive the catastrophe. The post-collapse 
survivors would know what used to be possible,  </text><text start="529.76" dur="4.08">and they could reverse engineer some 
of the tools and machines they’d find.</text><text start="534.4" dur="3.92">In conclusion, despite the bleak 
prospect of catastrophic threats,  </text><text start="538.32" dur="4.16">natural or created by ourselves, 
there is reason for optimism:  </text><text start="542.48" dur="5.92">humankind is remarkably resilient, and even in 
the case of a global civilizational collapse,  </text><text start="548.4" dur="5.76">it seems likely that we would be able to recover 
– Even if many people were to perish or suffer  </text><text start="554.16" dur="5.52">immense hardship. Even if we lost cultural 
and technological achievements in the process.</text><text start="560.56" dur="6.16">But given the stakes, the risks are still 
unnervingly high. Nuclear war and dangerous  </text><text start="566.72" dur="6.48">pandemics threaten the amazing global civilization 
we have built. Humanity is like a teenager,  </text><text start="573.2" dur="5.84">speeding around blind corners, drunk, without 
a seat belt. The good news is that it is still  </text><text start="579.04" dur="5.28">early enough to prepare for and to mitigate 
these risks. We just need to actually do it.</text><text start="585.68" dur="2.56">We made this video together with Will MacAskill,  </text><text start="588.24" dur="5.44">a Professor of Philosophy at Oxford and one of 
the founders of the effective altruism movement,  </text><text start="593.68" dur="3.68">which is about doing the most good 
you can with your time and money.</text><text start="597.36" dur="3.6">Will just published a new book 
called What We Owe The Future,  </text><text start="600.96" dur="3.76">which is about how YOU can positively 
impact the long-term future of our  </text><text start="604.72" dur="4.8">world. If you like Kurzgesagt videos, 
the chances are high you will like it!</text><text start="610.08" dur="2.8">The book has some pretty 
counter intuitive arguments,  </text><text start="612.88" dur="4.88">like that risks from new technology, such 
as AI and synthetic biology, are at least as  </text><text start="617.76" dur="4.72">grave as those from climate change. Or that 
the world doesn’t contain too many people,  </text><text start="622.48" dur="5.92">but too few. And especially that everyday 
actions like recycling or refusing to fly  </text><text start="628.4" dur="4.32">just aren’t that big a deal compared to 
where you donate, or what career you pursue.</text><text start="633.36" dur="3.36">Most importantly, it argues 
that, by acting wisely,  </text><text start="636.72" dur="4.24">YOU can help make tomorrow better 
than today. And how WE together  </text><text start="640.96" dur="4.88">can build a flourishing world for the thousands or 
millions of generations that will come after us.  </text><text start="646.48" dur="5.6">Many things we at Kurzgesagt talk about regularly 
are discussed here, in much greater detail.</text><text start="652.08" dur="4.08">Check out What We Owe The Future wherever 
you get your books or audiobooks.</text><text start="658.88" dur="3.12">Did we manage to unlock a new fear for you?</text><text start="662.88" dur="4.08">Let’s counter existential dread 
with appreciation for humanity.</text><text start="667.52" dur="3.44">Look how far we’ve come as 
a species. What we’ve built  </text><text start="670.96" dur="16.88">and where we’ve gathered. Let this new World 
Map Poster be a reminder of what we can achieve.</text></transcript>