<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="3.42" dur="5.6">Today’s high-speed trains will have you cruising along at 350 kilometres per hour.</text><text start="9.02" dur="2">A ticket is about the same as a flight,</text><text start="11.02" dur="2.8">and the door-to-door time on some of the world’s most popular routes</text><text start="13.82" dur="2.64">is the same, or less than getting a plane.</text><text start="17.76" dur="2.44">But decades ago rail travel was in decline.</text><text start="20.2" dur="3.24">It faced fierce competition from the air and auto industries.</text><text start="23.9" dur="2">Then came Japan&amp;#39;s bullet train.</text><text start="30.86" dur="4.8">By the late 1950s, Japan’s economic miracle had transformed the war ravaged nation.</text><text start="35.66" dur="2">Its economy was growing quickly.</text><text start="37.66" dur="3.38">The area between Tokyo and Osaka was booming with industry.</text><text start="41.56" dur="2.3">People were flocking to the capital for work</text><text start="43.86" dur="3.22">but the rail line connecting the two major cities couldn’t take the stress.</text><text start="47.66" dur="3.38">In 1958, a government panel was set up to tackle the problem</text><text start="51.04" dur="2.7">and several potential solutions arose.</text><text start="53.74" dur="3.02">Among them, building the world’s first high-speed rail line.</text><text start="57.3" dur="3.16">Many were skeptical, but two men were true believers.</text><text start="60.84" dur="4.54">Shinji Sogō was the then president of the state-run Japanese National Railways.</text><text start="65.38" dur="3.58">The other, Sogō’s colleague, veteran engineer Hideo Shima.</text><text start="69.76" dur="5.2">Up against bureaucratic obstacles and fierce opposition - the two drove the project forward.</text><text start="77.3" dur="5.18">In 1959, the Tōkaidō Shinkansen line started construction under Sogō’s leadership.</text><text start="82.68" dur="2.46">Shima was appointed the project’s chief engineer.</text><text start="85.14" dur="3.72">His team designed the sleek and revolutionary cone-shaped front -</text><text start="88.86" dur="1.96">from which the bullet train got its name.</text><text start="91.42" dur="2">Rather than being pulled by an engine in front,</text><text start="93.42" dur="3.94">each carriage of the bullet train was driven by an individual electric motor,</text><text start="97.36" dur="3.52">which has proven to be safer, faster and more efficient.</text><text start="101.3" dur="3.96">Apart from the train itself, the team also built wider tracks,</text><text start="105.26" dur="3.62">which were more costly but allowed for greater stability and higher speeds.</text><text start="109.4" dur="5.32">3,000 bridges and 67 tunnels were built on the 515-kilometer line</text><text start="114.72" dur="2.38">to allow a clear and largely curveless path.</text><text start="117.1" dur="2.08">Older trains were banned from the new line.</text><text start="119.44" dur="2.76">Equipped with advanced technologies, the new trains were able to</text><text start="122.2" dur="2.44">travel as fast as 210 kilometers per hour,</text><text start="124.64" dur="3.98">a breakthrough in the passenger rail industry and the world’s fastest at the time.</text><text start="128.98" dur="4">The journey time between Tokyo and Osaka was cut from over 6 hours to 4.</text><text start="134.3" dur="3.22">On October 1, 1964, the new line opened,</text><text start="137.52" dur="2">just in time for the Tokyo Olympic Games.</text><text start="147.3" dur="3.42">But neither Sogō’ nor Shima were invited for the inauguration.</text><text start="151.58" dur="1.92">They both resigned in 1963</text><text start="153.5" dur="3.18">because the project’s budget came in at double what was promised -</text><text start="156.68" dur="4.5">400 billion yen, the equivalent of 3.6 billion US dollars today.</text><text start="162.04" dur="2">But despite their premature departure,</text><text start="164.04" dur="3.98">the Tōkaidō Shinkansen line was an immediate success and quickly turned a profit.</text><text start="168.36" dur="1.44">It transformed the nation -</text><text start="169.8" dur="2">allowing more people to work in metropolitan areas</text><text start="171.8" dur="4.5">and became a symbol of Japan’s postwar re-emergence as an economic and tech power.</text><text start="179.14" dur="3.28">Now over 300 trains operate on the line everyday.</text><text start="182.42" dur="4.32">And the trip between Tokyo and Osaka has shortened to two and a half hours.</text><text start="186.74" dur="2.34">The number of passengers has also soared,</text><text start="189.08" dur="2.72">reaching 165 million in 2016.</text><text start="192.46" dur="2.48">After the success of the Tōkaidō Shinkanse line,</text><text start="194.94" dur="2.36">Japan has continued expanding its high-speed</text><text start="197.3" dur="2.24">rail network and plans to build more.</text><text start="200.76" dur="3.12">Following Japan’s lead, countries like France, Germany and China</text><text start="203.88" dur="2.46">have also developed high-speed railways.</text><text start="206.34" dur="2.92">By the end of 2018, the total length of high-speed</text><text start="209.26" dur="3.76">rail network in the world will be over 46,000 kilometers,</text><text start="213.68" dur="2">and over half of it is in China.</text></transcript>