<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="1.32" dur="2.68">The decision whether one should stay or leave</text><text start="4" dur="4.42">is one of the most consequential
and painful any of us ever has to make.</text><text start="8.5" dur="3.44">On any given day, many millions of people worldwide</text><text start="11.94" dur="4.94">will be secretly turning the issue over in their minds
as they go about their daily lives.</text><text start="16.88" dur="6.04">Their partners beside them, possibly having little clue as to the momentous decision weighing upon them.</text><text start="23.12" dur="3.2">The choice is perhaps more common now than it ever was</text><text start="26.82" dur="4.32">We expect to be deeply happy in love, and, therefore, spend a good deal of time</text><text start="31.14" dur="5.96">wondering whether our relationships are essentially normal in their sexual and psychological frustrations</text><text start="37.1" dur="6.22">or are beset by unusually pathological patterns which will impel us to get out as soon as we can.</text><text start="43.32" dur="4.36">What films or novels we&amp;#39;ve been exposed to, the state of our friends&amp;#39; relationships,</text><text start="47.68" dur="6.08">the degree of noise surrounding new sexually driven dating apps, not to mention how much sleep we&amp;#39;ve had</text><text start="53.78" dur="5.42">can all play humblingly large roles in influencing us one way or another.</text><text start="59.44" dur="4.76">Awkwardly, it seems that no one else actually really minds what we end up doing</text><text start="64.2" dur="5.62">which gives the decision a degree of existential loneliness it might not always have possessed</text><text start="69.98" dur="3.06">Historically, the choice was, in a sense, a good deal easier</text><text start="73.1" dur="5.34">because there were simply so many stern external sanctions around not leaving:</text><text start="78.58" dur="3.2">religions would insist that god blessed unions</text><text start="81.78" dur="2.58">and would be furious that they&amp;#39;re being torn asunder,</text><text start="84.36" dur="2.6">society strongly disapproved of breakups</text><text start="86.98" dur="4.24">and cast separating parties into decades of ignominy and shame,</text><text start="91.24" dur="4.94">and psychologists would explain that children would be deeply and permanently scarred</text><text start="96.34" dur="3.1">by any termination in their parents&amp;#39; relationship</text><text start="99.74" dur="4.14">But, one by one, these objections to quitting have fallen away;</text><text start="104.06" dur="2.72">religions no longer terrify us into staying</text><text start="106.9" dur="1.52">society doesn&amp;#39;t care,</text><text start="108.42" dur="2.64">and psychologists now routinely tell us that children</text><text start="111.24" dur="3.04">would prefer a broken family to an unhappy one</text><text start="114.72" dur="4.32">The burden of choice therefore falls squarely on us.</text><text start="119.18" dur="4.32">The only thing determining whether to stay or leave is how we feel</text><text start="123.5" dur="3.86">which can be pretty hard matter indeed to work out for ourselves,</text><text start="127.36" dur="6.18">our feelings having a dispirited habit of shifting and evading any efforts of rational qualification.</text><text start="133.54" dur="6.58">In the circumstances, it might help to have a set of questions, devil&amp;#39;s advocate in nature, to fall back upon -</text><text start="140.12" dur="3.14">a kind of checklist to dialogue within one&amp;#39;s mind</text><text start="143.26" dur="4.76">in the silent hours of the morning, from the chill vantage point of the spare room couch.</text><text start="148.58" dur="5.52">How much of our unhappiness can be tightly attributed to this particular partner,</text><text start="154.22" dur="5.78">and how much might it, as we would risk discovering five years and multiple upheavals later,</text><text start="160.02" dur="6.72">turn out to be simply and inherent feature of any attempt to live in close proximity to another human?</text><text start="166.74" dur="3.46">Though it is, of course, always essentially their fault,</text><text start="170.22" dur="6.56">what tiny proportion of the difficulties might we, nevertheless, be contributing to the discord?</text><text start="176.78" dur="5.22">In what modest way might we be a little hard to be around?</text><text start="182.62" dur="3.68">Consider the annoying traits in all previous partners we&amp;#39;ve had</text><text start="186.3" dur="4.58">and people we&amp;#39;ve known that our current partners happen not to have</text><text start="190.88" dur="3.22">what do we manage not to fight about?</text><text start="194.42" dur="6.24">Start to probe at any new infatuations or crushes, largely by getting to know them better</text><text start="200.82" dur="4.64">Observe closely how many sexually available and intelligent people</text><text start="205.46" dur="6.88">the single types around us, especially those hooked up to those new dating apps actually manage to encounter day-to-day.</text><text start="213.5" dur="4.64">Try to have another converstaion with your partner in which you don&amp;#39;t accuse them of mendacity,</text><text start="218.36" dur="6.84">and instead simply explain, quite calmly, how you actually feel and how sad you are at quite a few things.</text><text start="225.92" dur="2.74">Reflect on how&amp;#39;d you really feel as a child.</text><text start="228.72" dur="3.36">If henceforth, you were to have two tiny bedrooms,</text><text start="232.08" dur="3.88">two new step-parents, and possibly a few more new half-siblings.</text><text start="236.4" dur="3.84">Compare with the scratchy reality of the current set up.</text><text start="241.2" dur="4.26">Question how normal it is for any couple to have great sex after twenty-two months.</text><text start="245.64" dur="4.92">Ask yourself if you&amp;#39;re ready to face the risk of perhaps achieving no more</text><text start="250.7" dur="6.82">than exchanging a familiar kind of unhappiness for a new and more complex variety of unhappiness.</text><text start="258.3" dur="5.46">Wonder whether you really want to choose hope over experience</text><text start="263.76" dur="2.56">Then, if you still have the impulse to leave,</text><text start="266.32" dur="5.3">the chances of subsiquent regret lessened to at least a touch, a heavy heart, and a cautious mind,</text><text start="272.3" dur="1.2">leave.</text></transcript>